グオ！
わっ 本当だ 膨らんだ！
You’re right!
It’s swelling up!
シャ～ッ！
んっ…
グオ～
グオ…
FROM
THE
NEW
WORLD
No way…
ウソ…
This can’t be!
いや
これ… 風船犬の…
Is this part of the blowdog?
I’m pretty sure it’s a bone.
骨だよ きっと
ウソだろ…
You’re kidding me…
何してんの？
What are you doing?
なんか
花火みたいな においがする
It kinda smells like fireworks.
そうか なるほどね
I see. That explains it.
あっ… 本当に殺すためだけに
進化するなんて あるの？
So some creatures really evolve just to kill?
種は 生き残るためなら
何だってするんだよ…
They do whatever it takes for their species to survive.
Saki…
早季…
Anyway, let’s get out of here.
とにかく 引き返そう
ここに固まってても絶好の的だ
We’re sitting ducks here.
Hey…
おい
あっ… どうするの！
呪力がないのに どうするの
What now?
We’re helpless without our Canti!
シ～ッ！
アイツらは まだ分かんねえってば
Shh. They don’t know that yet.
逃げ腰んところ見せたら
調子にのって追ってくるぞ
If we start running away now,
they’ll get confident and start chasing us.
でも ここにいたら
やっぱり襲われちゃうよ
But they’ll attack us anyway if we just stand here!
Yeah! Let’s run!
そうよ 逃げよ
アイツら
絶対に 戦いたがってないと思う
I’m pretty sure they don’t want to fight.
私たちに帰ってもらいたいだけよ
They just want to drive us away.
はあ？ じゃ アイツらが帰れよ
They should walk away, then.
きっと 向こうに巣穴があるのよ
Their nest must be on the far side.
Pursuit on a Hot Night
こっちが怖がってると
思わせるのも まずいから…
We’re screwed if they think we’re afraid, so…
ゆっくりな ゆっくり
Slowly! Do it slowly!
あそこで戦いたくないみたいだ
They don’t seem to want to fight over there.
やっぱり 巣穴があったんだな
I guess that’s where their nest is.
そうなんでしょう
I think so too.
でも 十分
巣穴から遠ざかったら どうなるか
But what if we get far enough from their nest?
ワァイオ…
Run!
はっ 走れ！
ギッグギ～
固まるな バラバラに
Don’t stick together! Split up!
ガッガガガガ…
いや… 死にたくない
No…
I don’t wanna die…
Saki, are you okay?
早季 大丈夫か？
Satoru?
覚… うっ…
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
I can’t get up…
無理みたい あっ…
うっ… えい
走れる？
Can you run?
あれ… 筑波山…
Is that Mount Tsukuba?
Yeah.
じゃあ 歩こう
Come on, let’s walk.
ううん… もう 遅いわ
No, it’s too late now.
何 言ってるんだよ… うっ…
Don’t say that.
ガッガガガガ…
The others got away, right?
みんな… たぶん逃げたよね
I’m sure they did.
うん たぶんな
ガッガガガ
ヘッ… しゃべんなってか フッ…
覚…
So we’re not allowed to talk?
Satoru!
大丈夫
殺すなら とっくにやってる
It’s okay.
If they wanted to kill us, they would’ve long ago.
コイツら
今日 初めて呪力を見たんだ
Today was the first time they saw Cantus in action.
They wouldn’t simply—
だったら簡単には うっ…
覚！
Satoru!
覚…
ほら… 殺さない…
See? He didn’t kill me.
ガッガガガ…
We’re in a real bind.
もう ホント最低
How’s your wound, Satoru?
覚 ケガは？
全然 何ともないよ
血も乾いてるし…
It’s nothing, I’m telling you.
The blood’s dried already.
You’re bleeding here.
ほら ここ 血が出てる
Huh? Where?
えっ どこ？
ほら ここ
Over here.
覚
Satoru…
ボノボは
個体の緊張や ストレスが高まると
When stress and anxiety between individuals rise,
they vent it through intimate sexual behavior.
濃密な性的接触によって
解消します…
同性間や 未成熟な固体の場合でも
This also applies to immature individuals or individuals of the same sex…
ふう… 早季…
Saki?
ううん… なんでもない…
No, it’s nothing.
私が したげる
Let me do it.
じっとしていて
Don’t move.
ボノボ型の愛の社会へと
作り替えることが急務でした…
They considered it their immediate duty to
create a society of love similar to that of bonobos.
違う
No.
…a powerful attack inhibition was necessary.
強力な攻撃抑制を
与えることが不可欠でした
サルなんかじゃない
We aren’t monkeys.
どうした？
What’s wrong?
あっ 違うの… ほら あれっ！
Nothing, it’s just… Look…
Don’t they know what privacy is?
ちっ 邪魔なヤツだな
呪力なんかなくたって
人間には 知恵がある
Even without our Canti, we still have brains.
覚
Satoru?
オイッ ほらっ！
Hey, you.
グッ ギッダグ…
そんなに怒るなよ
Oh, calm down.
立ちっ放しで
腹が減ってるんだろう
You must be hungry from your long watch.
それ…
Is that…
Yep, it’s the fake egg of a haythatcher.
カヤノスズクリの偽卵だよ
Oh please, are you stupid?
はあ… バッカじゃないの
いくらバケネズミだって
そんなの食べないわよ
Not even queerats would eat that.
グッ ギッガグ…！
Aren’t they a foreign species?
コイツら 外来種だろ
意外と カヤノスズクリのこと
知らないんじゃないかって
Maybe they have no experience with haythatchers.
See?
｢な｣じゃないわよ
No, I don’t.
It’ll just be covered in poop and get really mad.
フンまみれにして
怒らせるだけじゃない
ガオ…
えっ！
They’re coming!
来てる 来てる 来てる…!
They’re coming! They’re coming!
I know! Just shut up!
分かってる！ うるさいわね
急げって！
Hurry!
急いでる！
I’m trying!
もう… やるしかねえ
We’ve got no choice.
こちらです 早く
This way.
Hurry!
Please, follow me quickly!
早く こちらへ
ああ…
こちらです
This way!
これって バケネズミの…
Isn’t this a queerat nest?
おケガは ありませんか？ 神様
Are you hurt,
gods?
神様？
Gods?
申し遅れました
Please excuse my rudeness.
私 塩屋虻コロニーの
奏上役を務めます
I am a messenger for the Robber Fly colony.
スクィーラと申します
Squealer is my name.
Fly 604
塩谷虻…
The Robber Fly colony…
こうして 我が コロニーに
神様が ご降臨なされるとは
What honor it is that you should grace our colony with your presence.
いやはや 今日は
実に めでたき日でございます
Today is truly an auspicious day.
And we have two young and beautiful gods as well…
それもお美しい若神様が ２柱も
何か 聞こえない？
Do you hear something?
何の音かしら
What could it be?
The queen is eagerly awaiting your arrival.
女王も お２人の到着を
今や遅しと 待っております
ゴゴ… グオ…
グガ…
アア… グオ…
Gods, you honor us
ガゥイサァ…
オヤイ… デンデドデウオ…
ゴーヴェイ… デス…
with your presence.
こちらこそ
女王様に お目通りできて
The honor is ours.
We are delighted to be in your presence.
うれしく思っています
グケオ… ガガ…
グエ…
女王は お２人を歓迎し
The queen welcomes you and shall
provide hospitality as befits visitors.
客人として きょうすと
申しております
おう…
R-Right.
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
グエ… ココ…
ギャウ！
グエ～ オエオ…
グオウ～！
グアエ！
グア…
やめて 殺さないで！
Stop! Don’t kill him!
Forgive Squealer!
スクィーラを許してあげて！
ギャウ…
おとりなし頂き
ありがとうございました ああ…
I thank you for your intervention.
おかげで命拾いをいたしました
You have saved my life.
まさか…
あなたを殺す訳ないでしょう ねえ
Did she really mean to kill you?
実は お２人に
お願い事がございますのですが…
We have a favor to ask of you.
The Feral Spider colony?
土蜘蛛コロニー
They are the foreign species that attacked you earlier.
先ほど 神様を襲った
外来種の者どものことで
ございます
数日前より 我々 在来種である
塩屋虻コロニーとの間で
Several days ago, they declared war on us, who have been native in these parts since time untold.
戦闘状態に突入いたしました
そうなんだ
I see.
勝てそうなの？
Are you winning?
いいえ 昨日 近隣の３つの
コロニーに特使をだしまして
No.
Yesterday we sent special envoys to three
neighboring colonies to plead for reinforcements,
救援を要請したところなんですが
到着するまでには
but it will take some time until they arrive.
今しばらくの時間が必要かと
考えます
じゃあ 今 攻めてこられたら
まずいんじゃないの？
So, you can’t afford to be attacked right now?
That’s right.
そうだよ！ 俺らが来なかったら
どうするつもりだったんだよ
What if we hadn’t come by?
はい お二方の若神様たちが
おいでになったのは
I am sure it is the will of the heavens that two young gods have come to save us from destruction.
私共を破滅から救う
天の ご意志であると心得ます
無礼を承知でお願いいたします
Excuse my rudeness and hear my plea.
あの神をも畏れぬ 土蜘蛛どもに
Bring down the iron hammer of vengeance on the Feral Spiders who fear not even the gods.
ようちょうの鉄ついを
下されますように
伏してお願い申し上げます
I implore you.
We’re really sorry, but we can’t do that.
申し訳ないけど
それは できないんだ
僕たちが
バケネズミに処分をくだす場合
We require permission to punish queerats.
許可がいるんだ
I am fully aware of that.
それは 重々 承知でございます
ですが このままでは
我々は 全滅を余儀なくされます
However, if no action is taken,
we will inevitably meet our end here.
I beg you.
どうか後生です 何とぞ
ヤツらに ささやかな打撃を
If you would strike only a modest blow at their ranks…
この戦いに負けたら
あなたたちは どうなるの？
If you lose this war, what would happen to you?
女王は 処刑され
The queen would be executed,
我々は 奴隷として
一生 酷使されます
and we would work as slaves until we die.
生きている限り
家畜以下の扱いを受け
We would be treated like scum while we live,
死ねば 野山に捨てられるか
and our corpses would be left in the hills to fertilize the earth.
畑の肥料となりましょう
だから 子供と バケネズミが
出会うことは
For that reason we have to keep children from meeting the queerats.
避けなきゃならないんだ
Satoru! Satoru!
覚… 覚？
なんだよ
What is it—
Shh.
ほら
Listen.
まさか 土蜘蛛のヤツら…
Could that be the Feral Spiders?
グオ～！
Do you remember which way we came?
どっちから来たか 覚えてる？
たぶん 合ってると思う
This is it, I think.
出口！
An exit!
吸っちゃダメだ！
Don’t breathe it!
えっ？
逃げろ！
Run!
こっち！
This way!
ググ… ガア！
ググ ガア…
うう！
ガア！
グガ…
うっ！
覚 あれ！
Satoru, look!
空か
It’s the sky.
あそこから 外に出られる
We can get out from there.
Yeah.
Satoru, hurry!
覚 早く！
覚… どうしたの？
What’s wrong, Satoru?
That’s…
そんな…
ウソよ…
No way…
覚！ はっ…
Satoru!
早季～！
Saki!
Episode 5
Pursuit on a Hot Night
Nakisou na aoringo kakaeteru mune no oku
泣きそうな青リンゴ  抱えてる胸の奥
In my chest, I carry a green apple that wets my eyes
Korogatte tsuyogatte
転がって  強がって
I fall over yet pretend to be strong
Kyuukutsu na sora niramu
窮屈な空睨む
I glower at the sky and it seems to suffocate me
Unmei ni juujun ni
運命に従順に
Do I look like I'd wait quietly
Jukusu no wo matsu mon ka
熟すのを待つもんか
For destiny to ripen it?
Sen no kaze
千の風
The winds
Agaite sakende
あがいて  叫んで
I struggle and scream
Fuke fuke
吹け吹け
Blow and blow
Watashi wa shabondama
わたしはしゃぼん玉
I'm a soap bubble
Soredemo shinjiteru
それでも信じてる
And still I have faith
Yokisenu arashi ni
予期せぬ  嵐に
In a sudden storm
Joushou shite kakou shite
上昇して  下降して
I rise and fall
Aragau shabondama
あらがうしゃぼん玉
I fight, soap bubble that I am
Soredemo ikiteku
それでも生きてく
And still I live on
Hajikeru shunkan niji hanate
弾ける瞬間  虹、放て
I make a rainbow when I burst
朝比奈 覚 朝比奈 覚…
Asahina Satoru. Asahina Satoru.
お前は 規則を破って
来てはならないところに来た
You have violated the rules and gone where you were not supposed to.
しかも 禁を犯して
Furthermore, you have allowed your mind to be poisoned by a demon.
悪魔の言葉に 耳を傾けた
だが 問題は その先にある
The real problem, however, weighs far heavier.